Guide to the Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
- Series IV. Outgoing Correspondence
  - Anne Elder Jackson
    - GBS: Autographed note initialed to Ann Elder, Aug.7, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 113, Folder 79)
      Prior's Field, Godalming; Enclosed are odds & ends taht I should have given you yesterday
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Aug.10, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 113, Folder 80)
      London; Was Miss Kaurer's a/c sent with the fees all right?
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Aug.13, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 1)
      Prior's Field, Godalming; If you can find a letter from A. E. Boyd (I am not sure of the initials)
    - GBS: Autographed note signed to Ann Elder, Sept.6, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 2)
      Prior's Field, Godalming; Please get on 15 one pound notes = 15 pounds
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.9, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 3)
      [n.p.] Stationery as follows/ 2 packets of envelopes, court size
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.13, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 4)
      Parknasilla Hotel, Kenmare, Co. Kerry; Please open all letters. The one you conjectured to be from Lucy
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.13, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 5)
      Parknasilla Hotel, Kenmare, Co. Kerry; During your absence the letters had better be forwarded to me:
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.16, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 6)
      Parknasilla Hotel, Kenmare, Co. Kerry; I am sending a letter to Miss Dickens to be mimeographed.
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.19, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 7)
      Parknasilla Hotel, Kenmare, Co. Kerry; If this reaches you in time, will you send me a file -
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.26, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 8)
      Parknasilla Hotel, Kenmare, Co. Kerry; There is no reason why you should hurry back to town.
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.30, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 9)
      Long Lake, Sneem, Co. Kerry; These are all for filing 2 c. [On verso is picture of Long Lake]
    - GBS: Autographed note initialed to Ann Elder, Oct.2, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 10)
      Parknasilla Hotel, Kenmare, Co. Kerry; I find that my prolonged stay is eating up my stationery.
    - GBS: Autographed note initialed to Ann Elder, Oct.3, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 11)
      Parknasilla Hotel, Kenmare, Co. Kerry; Please look in the letter H in the general file, also in K,
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Oct.12, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 12)
      Parknasilla Hotel, Kenmare, Co. Kerry; Please make two copies of the enclosed, and post the original immediately
    - GBS: Autographed letter signedto Ann Elder, Oct.17, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 13)
      Kilteragh, Foxrock, Co. Dublin; It is not settled that we leave this on the evening of next Tuesday,
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Oct.18, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 14)
      Kilteragh, Foxrock, Co. Dublin; Do not send any books here, especially bulky ones:
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Oct.28, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 15)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; Can you find any more photographs for me?
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Dec.9, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 16)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; Cable Foversham as follows: "Since calling have learnt that your operations have proved fatal...
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Dec.21, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 17)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; Please send me a memorandum of the payments I have to make at the end of the year.
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Dec.24, 1917; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 18)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; I cannot pay the Sussex Lodge rent without the receipt,
    - GBS: Autographed note initialed to Ann Elder, Jan.2, 1918; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 19)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; Have you any refills for the Reporters Note Book?
    - GBS: Autographed note initialed to Ann Elder, Mar.4, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 20)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; I got no letters this morning. Ask Una at what hour they must be posted.
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Apr.6, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 21)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; Please buy The Herald on Monday & Tuesday (2 copies would be no harm)
    - GBS: Autographed letter initialed to Ann Elder, Jul.15, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 22)
      Great Southern Hotel, Parknasilla-on-Sea; The enclosed finishes the third Methusulah play; and as I want to guard
    - GBS: Autographed letter initialed to Ann Elder, Jul.20, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 23)
      Great Southern Hotel, Parknasilla-on-Sea; I send the enclosed not to spoil your holiday (though it has so far spoiled mine)
    - GBS: Autographed letter initialed to Ann Elder, Aug.20, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 24)
      Great Southern Hotel, Parknasilla-on-Sea; Send Constance Collier the blue papper of terms and say that she can deduct
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Aug.25, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 25)
      Great Southern Hotel, Parknasilla-on-Sea; The word in the telegram was Cox.
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.1, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 26)
      The Hut, Bray, Berks.; Tomorrow (Tuesday) I go to Penbe. As they always bother me to recite
    - GBS: Autographed letter initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.10, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 27)
      Penbe near Dartmouth; On Friday morning I start for Presteign,
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.17, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 28)
      Presteign; At present it seems likely that I shall return on Saturday to Ayot
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Sept.23, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 29)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; I am comping up on Thursday. Tell Mrs. Bilton.
    - GBS: Autographed note initialed to Ann Elder, Oct.11, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 30)
      [n.p.] Say very politely that I do not understand the transaction
    - GBS: Autographed note initialed to Ann Elder, Dec.27, 1919; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 31)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; Please 1. Get one of the National Liberal Club pamphlets on Equality from the bundle
    - GBS: Autographed note initialed to Ann Elder, Jun.13, 1920; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 32)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; You did not put Eaglefield Hull's letter in my bag; so I cannot send the corrected
    - GBS: Autographed note initialed to Ann Elder, [n.d.]; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 33)
      [n.p.] Please send me down, The last Macdona-Pygmalion agreement
    - GBS: Autographed postcard initialed to Ann Elder, Dec.28, 1920; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 34)
      Ayot St. Lawrence; I am writing to Hugh Peed to send you a copy of Dr. Robert Bell's pamphlet:
    - GBS: Autographed letter initialed [copy] to Ann Elder, Apr.29, 1924; 1 leaf (Box 114, Folder 35)
      Shakespeare Hotel, Stratford-on-Avon; My dear Ann/ Send Miss Patch (your successor at the Terrace) your mother's name and address
- Series V. Manuscripts and Correspondence to and by others
  - A - B
    - Achurch, Janet: Autograph Letter Signed: to Felix Mansfield, Mar. 9, 1895; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 1)
      London; concerned with Miss Achurch's agreement to go on tour with Felix Mansfield, appearing in Shaw's Candida, among other plays; begins "Dear Mr. Mansfield / Thanks for your / letter. In answer to that"
    - Abdul Aziz, Mian, khan bahadur: Autograph Letter Signed: to Lord Birdwood (Field Marshal), Mar. 14, 1942; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 19, Folder 2)
      London; begins "Dear Lord Birdwood / I don't want to buy your book"
    - Aldrich, Richard Stoddard: Telegram to Blanche Patch, Sept. 6, 1952; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 3)
      New York; "Gertrude" is Gertrude Lawrence, she was married to Richard Aldrich; begins "Our Gertrude Joined Immortals Today"
    - Aldrich, Richard Stoddard: Autograph Note Signed: to Blanche Patch, Sept. 1952; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 4)
      New York; a note written on a note card printed with an acknowledgement of sympathy; begins "Dear Miss Patch / Your wonderful letter was"
    - Aldrich, Richard Stoddard: Christmas Card to Blanche Patch, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Arnaud, Yvonne: Autograph Note Signed: to Blanche Patch, Nov. 1957; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Begins "To my dear Miss Patch"
    - Arnaud, Yvonne: Autograph Note Signed: to Blanche Patch, Dec. 1957; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Surrey?; Christmas postcard; begins "A very Happy Xmas, and a very"
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher, Viscountess: Autograph Note Signed: to George Bernard Shaw, n.d.; card; 1 leaf + 1 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Cliveden; includes holograph transcription by Blanche Patch?; begins "Dearest G.B.S. / I see that Dr. F.E.L."
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher, Viscountess: Autograph Note Signed: to Blanche Patch, n.d.(Tuesday); card; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 9)
      Cliveden; begins "Dear Miss Patch / What a performance!"
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher, Viscountess: Typed Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, Jan. 1, 1943; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Cliveden; begins "Dear Patch, [holograph note 'Miss!! She left out the Miss'] Thank you so much for your"
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher, Viscountess: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, ca. Jan. 5, 1943; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Cliveden, Taplow, Bucks; written on the reverse side of a letter from F. Heritage, Private Secretary of teh Minstry of Labour and National Service, to the Viscountess Astor; begins "Dear Miss Patch / I may still come"
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher, Viscountess: Typed Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, June 25, 1945; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Plymouth; begins "Dear Miss Patch / I was so glad to get your letter"
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher, Viscountess: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, Feb. 4, 1947; postcard; 1 leaf + envelope + 1 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      Maidenhead; on the leaf containing the transcription of Lady Astor's letter [by Blanche Patch?] is another transcription of a later letter from Lady Astor, dated May 25, 1947; begins "Dear Miss Patch / Thank you so much for"
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher, Viscountess: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, May 25, 1947; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 14)
      Includes transcription filed with the February, 1947 letter; begins "Dear Miss Patch / G.B.S. wrote me he felt Cliveden"
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher (Langhorne), Viscountess: Typed Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, Mar. 18, 1948; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 15)
      Tuscon, Arizona; includes holograph notations; begins "Dear Miss Patch / I can't thank you enough for your letter"
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher, Viscountess: Typed Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, May 6, 1949; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 16)
      Plymouth; with holograph notation; begins "Dear Miss Patch / Thank you so much for writing me"
    - B, J W: Autograph Letter Signed: to Lucy Carr Shaw [initialed], Jan. 27, 1904; card; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 17)
      Wimborne; begins "Very many thanks for books."
    - Barker, Herbert: Autograph Letter Signed: to George Bernard Shaw, Sept. 17, 1943; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 18)
      Begins "Dear Bernard Shaw / I cannot tell you"
    - Bateman, Henry Mayo: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, Dec. 3, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 19)
      London; regarding a drawing Bateman was to make of Shaw; begins "Dear Miss Patch / Thank you for your"
    - Baty, Thomas: Autograph Note Signed: to George Bernard Shaw, Dec. 29, 1921; postcard; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 20)
      Postcard from the Orient?; begins "As a close friend of H.S. Salt, I venture to"
    - Beatty, Pakeham Thomas: Envelopes addressed to George Bernard Shaw, using different nicknames. From Feb.; Mar. 20; May 2; Sept. 18; Oct. 15, 29; Nov. 6, 19, 1833; 8 leaves + 1 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Includes card of identification in Shaw's hand, but with date of receipt assigned to 1882
    - Beerbohm, Max: Drawing of H.G. Wells, G. Bernard Shaw, and Sidney Webb [others identified in Beerbohm's A Survey, 1921], before 1921; 1 leaf + 2 (Box 19, Folder 22)
      Inscribed "Tout peut se rétablir," Rupert Hart-Davis calls it "a first sketch for the finished drawing, which is now in the Ashmolean Museum in Oxford."
    - Beerbohm, Max: "The Iconoclast's One Friend", 1 leaf (Box Mapcase, Folder B-17)
      Caricature, in pen and watercolour, of Shaw and a member of "Mrs. Warren's Profession". [In folder marked "Caricatures]
    - Beresford[?], J.D.: Autograph Letter Signed: to George Bernard Shaw, Nov. 27, 1922; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 23)
      London; begins "Dear Mr. Shaw, I wonder if you could spare"
    - No box 19, folder 24 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Besant, Annie (Wood): Autograph Letter Signed: to Mr. Thies, Feb. 11, 1887; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 25)
      London; begins "Dear Mr. Thies, I will keep the"
    - Bishop, George Walter: Typed Manuscript: in Shaw's or Bishop's hand, Aug. 18, 1930; 19 leaves + envelope (Box 19, Folder 26)
      Malvern; filed with Typed Manuscript by G.W. Bishop concerning the second Malvern Festival; possibly Shaw saw and corrected the manuscript before it was printed
    - Bishop, George Walter: Typed Manuscript: "Mr. Shaw and Frank Harris; A Reply to the Critics.", 1931; 5 leaves (Box 19, Folder 27)
      Concerns the biography of Shaw by Frank Harris
    - Bliss, Gorham: Typed Letter Signed: to John Farleigh, July 28, 1937; 2 leaves (Box 19, Folder 28)
      West Springfield, Mass.; Worthy Paper Company Association; begins "Dear Sir: At the request of Mr. George Macy"
    - Bolgarkoff, Elena: Autograph Letter Signed: to George Bernard Shaw, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 29)
      London; request for an appointment with Shaw; begins "Sir / Please be kind anaf [sic] to see"
    - Brentano's, New York: Typed Letter: to George Bernard Shaw, Aug. 27, 1920; carbon copy; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 30)
      Found among letters received from Shaw by Brentano's; begins "Dear Sir: We beg to enclose check on London"
    - Brieux, Eugène: Autograph Letter Signed: to Brentano's, July 30, 1912; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 31)
      St. Hilaire-Sur-Puiseaux Par Vimory (Loiret); found among letters received from Shaw by Brentano's; begins "Monsieur, Je vous"
    - British Broadcasting Corporation: Typed Manuscript: B.B.C. Broadcast English, Feb. 1947; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 32)
      London; begins "Over the period of its existence"
    - Brome, Vincent: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, June 24, 1955; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 33)
      London; begins "Dear Miss Patch, Forgive this scrap of paper"
    - Brooks, Cecil L.: Typed Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, Apr. 9, 1951; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 34)
      London; the letterhead is The Incorporated Press of Great Britain, Ltd.; begins "Dear Miss Patch, Thank you so much for sending the autographed photograph."
    - Burgunder, Bernard F.: Typed Manuscript: Introduction of Dan H. Laurence, [Oct.17, 1975]; manuscript; 1 leaf + copy (Box 19, Folder 34.5)
      Introduction at Cornell University Lecture, Ithaca, NY
    - Burgunder, Bernard F.: Typed Manuscript: Last Will and Testament, July 24, 1981; copy; 9 leaves + 4 + 1 (Box 19, Folder 35)
      With 4 leaves of codicils, and with Typed Letter Signed to James Tyler from Arthur Silverblatt, March 20, 1986
    - Burgunder, Bernard F.: Notes on Shaw's play Fanny's First Play, Sept. 1960; typescript; 13 pages (Box 19, Folder 36)
      Regarding the first proof and a prompt copy; including a two-page postscript of June 1961
    - Burgunder, Bernard F.: Autograph Manuscript: Notes to Loewenstein, ca. 1956-1978; 1 item (Box 19, Folder 37)
      Bernard Burgunder's copy, annotated to record acquisitions for the Shaw Collection, of F.E. Loewenstein's The Rehearsal Copies of Bernard Shaw's Plays(London 1950); gift of the Estate of Bernard F. Burgunder; an unmarked copy of the book is shelved as SHAW Z 8814.5 L82 1950
    - Burgunder, Bernard F.: Manuscript: Obituaries, Mar. 1986; 11 leaves + 1 item (Box 19, Folder 38)
      Obituary announcements and related information; Bernard Frank Burgunder, donor of the Burgunder Shaw Collection, died on March 3, 1986; included is the printed Eulogy of Bernard F. Burgunder spoken at the memorial service by Tom Bigler
    - Burgunder, Bernard F.: Typed Letter Signed: to Preston C. Beyer. From Mar. 15, 1977; June 9, June 26, and Sept. 7, 1981, 1977, 1981; 4 leaves + 1 (Box 19, Folder 39)
      Gift of Preston C. Beyer; with his typed and initialled note dated Nov. 17, 1986
    - Burgunder, Bernard F.: Typed Letter Signed: to Joan Winterkorn, July 9, 1979 - May 25, 1982; 24 leaves (Box 19, Folder 40)
      23 letters; gift of Joan Winterkorn, October 1987; the letters are addressed to her at Bernard Quaritch Ltd. in London, where she assisted Mr. Burgunder in acquiring material for the Burgunder Shaw Collection at Cornell; Mrs. Winterkorn was previously a staff member of the Department of Rare Books at Cornell
    - Burns, John: Autograph Letter Signed: to George Bernard Shaw, Sept. 11, 1907; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 41)
      Cassel; date added in upper left corner in Shaw's hand[?] 22/9/07; begins "Dear Shaw / Delighted to hear your accident was not"
    - Butt, Dame Clara Ellen (later Rumford): Autograph Letter Signed: to George Bernard Shaw, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 42)
      begins "Dear Bernard Shaw / Thank you a thousand"
    - Butterfield, Lucinda Frances Carr (Shaw): Autograph Letter Signed: to George Bernard Shaw [initialed], Oct. 24, 1907; postcard; 1 leaf + 2 (Box 19, Folder 43)
      Includes a picture of the sender, Shaw's sister; with holograph note by Bernard Shaw "Sent £100 26/10/07;" begins "Gotha Wielaufe, ach du Herr"
    - Byers, J.S.R.: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, Feb. 24, 1962; 1 leaf (Box 19, Folder 44)
      Newcastle, N. Ireland; begins "Dear Madam / Recently you gave"
  - Campbell
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Typed Manuscript: Pygmalion script [fragment] and two drawings of GBS doodled on the reverse, copy; 2 leaves (Box 20, Folder 1)
      As Mrs. Campbell played "Eliza" in Pygmalion perhaps this fragment is part of one of her scripts; part of the Agnius Claudius-Mrs. Campbell material
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Manuscript: A talk on beautiful speech and vocal control..., copy; 23 leaves (Box 20, Folder 2)
      The beginning of a speech on diction and voice tone, hand-printed or written in oversized letters; also included is an additional page written in French
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Note: to Agnes Claudius, n.d.; envelope; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 3)
      Inscribed, "easter greetings to my friend of the Magnetic[?] face My beautiful Egypt;" also includes a holograph drawing of a bird and flowers, on the same envelope
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Letter Signed and Typed Letter Signed: to Arthur Bertram, ca. 1876 - 1910; 25 leaves (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Mostly undated, handwritten letters, to her business manager
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Typed Letter: to Mary Augusta Ward, Oct. 17, 1901; 1 leaf + 7 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      With a revised draft of the same letter, and with a draft and typed copy of a telegram circa October 15 from Mrs. P.C. to M.A. Ward; and with an unsigned letter dated Sept. 3, 1901, presumably from Arthur Bertram to Mrs. Ward's agent; all items concern production of Mrs. Ward's play Eleanor
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Letter Signed: to George Bernard Shaw, Apr. 29, 1914; 1 leaf + 2 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      With typed transcription by Dan Laurence and a note by Bernard F. Burgunder; date in Shaw's hand; begins "His Majesty's Theatre [London] / I have just had this letter from Klaw."
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Letter Signed: to Viola Tree, ca. Feb. 1920; 2 leaves (Box 20, Folder 7)
      Chelsea; concerns the form in which Mrs. P.C.'s part in Pygmalion is to be announced; begins "Viola darling - Please don't let / Joey get us by the / ears!"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Letter Signed: to Blanche Patch, July 21, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 8)
      London; begins "Dear Miss Patch, Thanks so very"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Typed Manuscript: Chance-Medley, Feb. - Aug. 1936; carbon copy; 258 leaves + envelope + 3 + 3 photographs (Box 20, Folder 9)
      The typed title "Random Reminiscences" is changed, in Mrs. Campbell's hand, to "Chance-Medley;" the envelope is addressed in her hand, apparently to an agent or prospective publisher, but most corrections in the manuscript seem to be in another hand; three inscribed photographs of her accompany the manuscript; includes 2 leaves of explanatory notes by B.F. Burgunder, and copy of the auction catalog listing; WHENEVER POSSIBLE USE PHOTOCOPY, NOT THIS ORIGINAL.
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Typed Letter Signed: to George Bernard Shaw, Sept. 26, 1937; 2 leaves (Box 20, Folder 10)
      New York; regarding the correspondence between Mrs. Campbell and Shaw, and its possible publication; begins "Dear Joey, They have arrived safely after taking nearly three"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Letter Signed: to Agnes Claudius, n.d.; 3 leaves (Box 20, Folder 11)
      begins "Dear Egypt. Dont [sic] let your Italian friend feel uncomfortable"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Letter Signed: to Agnes Claudius, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 12)
      begins "Dear Egypt. Joan write[sic] this address"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Typed Letter Signed: to Agnes Claudius, 1938?; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 13)
      Sirmione?; begins "My dear. It seems to me that perhaps"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Typed Letter Signed: to Agnes Claudius, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 14)
      Miss Claudius was a friend of Mrs. Campbell in her later years, caring for Stella when she died; begins "My dear. I am sending you the trunk as I promised"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Typed Letter Signed: to Agnes Claudius [initialed], 1938; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 15)
      Sirmione?; begins "Dea[sic] Dear Egypt. I am afraid I left my stick agains the rail"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Letter Signed: to Agnes Claudius [initialed], 1938; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 16)
      Sirmione; begins "My dear. If you can do buy"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Letter Signed: to Agnes Claudius, summer, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 17)
      Sirmione; begins "My dear / What a beautiful"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Typed Letter Signed: to Agnes Claudius, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 18)
      Hotel Sirmione, Sirmione; begins "Oh my dear dear Egypt. I do hope I was not unkind-"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Note Signed: to Agnes Claudius, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 19)
      Begins "Could I see"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Letter Signed: to Jenette Curtis, Apr. - May? 1938; 1 leaf + 1 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      New York; with explanatory note on separate leaf by Bernard F. Burgunder; begins "My dear / What marvellous / __ ! I am / better"
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Autograph Letter Signed: to Jennette Curtis, Apr. 20, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 21)
      New York; received August 1984 from Miss Frances Tompkins with other letters by Mrs. Campbell to Mrs. Curtis, and two letters by Agnes Claudius to Mrs. Curtis; Cf. Mrs. Pat, by Margot Peters (New York: Knopf, 1984); begins "Thank you my dear / for your cheque."
    - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick: Typed Letter Signed: to Jennette Curtis, June 3, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 20, Folder 22)
      New York; begins "My dear. That was no more a lesson than my hat!"